nagr.org 2019-07-04

# Privacy Policy - National Association for Gun Rights

## NAGR Privacy Policy

**NAGR PRIVACY NOTICE**

Privacy is very important to the National Association for Gun Rights (NAGR). As part of the normal operation of our services we may collect information about you. This Privacy Notice describes the information we collect about you and what may happen to that information. The privacy practices of this statement apply to the [www.nationalgunrights.org](http://www.nationalgunrights.org/), [www.nagr.org](http://www.nagr.org/), and any other web site used by the National Association for Gun Rights.

**The Information We Collect**

At some NAGR sites, you may be able to make contributions, sign petitions, complete surveys, vote in polls or otherwise express an opinion or participate. The types of personally identifiable information that may be collected at these pages include: name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, and information about your interests in and use of various programs and policies.

We also may collect certain non-personally identifiable information when you visit many of our web pages such as the type of browser you are using (e.g.,Firefox, Internet Explorer), the type of operating system you are using, (e.g., Windows Vista or Mac OSX) and the domain name of your Internet service provider (e.g., Verizon, AOL, Comcast).

We may use the information you provide about yourself to fulfill your requests for our programs, to respond to your inquiries, and to contact you about future programs that we believe may be of interest to you. An option to opt-out from this communication is provided in every contact and is performed automatically at your request. Moreover, we may use the information that you provide about others to enable us to send them additional information. In addition, NAGR may on occasion combine information we receive online with outside records to enhance our ability to contact you about programs that may be of interest to you.

The information we collect in connection with our websites is used to provide an interactive experience. We use this information to facilitate participation in grassroots lobbying, fundraising, and other programs. We sometimes use the non-personally identifiable information that we collect to improve the design and content of our site and to enable us to personalize your Internet experience. We also may use this information in the aggregate to analyze site usage.

Agents and contractors of NAGR who have access to personally identifiable information are required to protect this information in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Notice by, for example, not using the information for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for NAGR.

On occasion, some of our sites may contain links to other sites whose information practices may be different than ours. Visitors should consult the other sites' privacy notices as we have no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by, these third parties.

**Cookies**

To enhance your experience with our sites, our web pages may use "cookies." Cookies are text files we place in your computer's browser to store your preferences. Cookies, by themselves, do not tell us your e-mail address or other personally identifiable information. However, once you choose to furnish the site with personally identifiable information, this information may be linked to the data stored in the cookie.

We use cookies to understand site usage and to improve the content and offerings on our sites. For example, we may use cookies to personalize your experience at our web pages (e.g., to recognize you by name when you return to our site), or to save your password in password-protected areas.

**Our Commitment to Security**

We have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and help prevent unauthorized access, maintain data security, and correctly use the information we collect online. We do not save your credit card information, nor provide this information to any third party.
